These auralin and novodra columns violate the first rule of tidiness only,
تنتهك أعمدة auralin وnovodra القاعدة الأولى للترتيب فقط،
that each variable forms a column.
بحيث يشكل كل متغير عمودًا.
There are three variables here: treatment, auralin or novodra,
هناك ثلاثة متغيرات هنا: العلاج ، auralin أو novodra،
start dose, for example 41 units here,
جرعة البداية ، على سبيل المثال 41 وحدة هنا،
and then end dose,
والجرعة النهاية،
for example 48 units here.
على سبيل المثال 48 وحدة هنا.
So since there are three variables here there should be three columns
لذلك بما أن لدينا ثلاثة متغيرات هنا، يجب أن يكون هناك ثلاثة أعمدة
and there are currently two and both contain two variables.
ويوجد حاليًا اثنان منها ويحتوي كلاهما على متغيرين.
The auralin column contains the start and end dose for auralin patients and
يحتوي عمود auralin على جرعة البداية والنهاية لمرضى auralin
the novodra column contains the start
ويحتوي عمود novodra على جرعة البداية
and end dose for patients that were treated with novodra.
والنهاية للمرضى الذين تم علاجهم بـ novodra.
If these two columns both contain two variables,
إذا كان كلا العمودين يحتويان على متغيرين،
start and end dose each,
جرعة البداية والنهاية لكل منهما،
where is that missing third variable?
أين المتغير الثالث المفقود؟
We said there were three variables here, right?
قلنا أن هناك ثلاثة متغيرات هنا، أليس كذلك؟
Well, the third variable,
حسنًا، المتغير الثالث،
treatment, is hidden in the column headers here.
العلاج، مخفي في رؤوس الأعمدة هنا.
This is actually one of the most common tidiness issues as per Hadley Wickham.
هذا في الواقع أحد مشكلات الترتيب الأكثر شيوعا وفقا لـ Hadley Wickham.
Column headers are values not variable names.
رؤوس الأعمدة هي قيم وليست أسماء متغيرة.
So auralin and novodra are our values for the treatment variable.
لذا، فإن auralin و novodra هي قيمنا لمتغير العلاج.
Whoever structured the data set like this didn't plan very
أي شخص ينظم مجموعة البيانات بمثل هذه الطريقة يكون قد خطط بشكل غير
well and wasn't aware of the advantages of tidy data.
جيد ولم يكن على دراية بمزايا البيانات المرتبة.
The final product should look like this.
يجب أن يكون المنتج النهائي هكذا.
Let's zoom in here a bit.
دعونا نكبر الصورة هنا قليلًا.
So, for the first patient, Veronika Jindrova, she was treated with auralin,
لذا، بالنسبة للمريض الأول، Veronika Jindrova، تم علاجها بـ auralin
the auralin insulin, with the starting dose of 41 units and an ending dose of 48 units.
(ما يعرف بـ auralin insulin)، مع جرعة بداية بـ 41 وحدة وجرعة نهاية بـ 48 وحدة.
Auralin, 41, 48.
Auralin (41، 48).
Then for Elliot Richardson he was treated with novodra.
أما بالنسبة لـ Elliot Richardson كان يعالج بـ novodra.
Starting dose of 40 units,
جرعة بداية بـ 40 وحدة
ending dose of 45 units and novodra, 40, 45.
وجرعة نهاية بـ 45 وحدة. وnovodra (40، 45).
Three separate variables in three separate columns.
ثلاثة متغيرات منفصلة في ثلاثة أعمدة منفصلة.
Treatment, start dose, end dose.
العلاج، جرعة البداية، وجرعة النهاية.
You'll learn how to convert the two columns on
ستتعلمون كيفية تحويل العمودين
the left to the three columns on the right,
على اليسار إلى الأعمدة الثلاثة على اليمين
programmatically using the melt function and split method in Pandas next lesson.
برمجيًا باستخدام دالة الانصهار وطريقة التقسيم في الدرس القادم في Pandas.
The melt function specifically is really
دالة الانصهار على وجه التحديد مفيدة
handy but it can be confusing especially if you never seen it before.
وسهلة حقا، لكنها يمكن أن تكون مربكة خاصة إذا لم يسبق لكم رؤيتها من قبل.
Next lesson you'll conquer that.
وفي الدرس القادم سنتغلب على هذا الأمر.
So let's document this second tidiness issue.
لذا دعونا نسجل مشكلة الترتيب الثانية هذه.
And there we go. Here's our observation.
وها نحن نكمل الدرس. ها هي ملاحظتنا.